[head=2]Field Deployment[/head]

The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] and The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] have the right to deploy themselves to the frontline for the sake of commanding their troops from a more direct point of view than a ship’s Combat Information Centre. Deployments must be made for the sake of the troops, not for the personal glory or agenda of the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] themselves. This right does not extend to the Duty Officer.


[head=3]Deployment Prerequisites[/head]

Executive Officers are allowed to deploy in a Commanding Officer’s stead for leadership and are subject to the same regulations and standards as a CO.

For this passage, both the CO and XO together are referred to as the “Commanders”.

Should either the Commanding Officer or Executive Officer deploy, several rules must be followed:

- It is inadvised for the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] and Executive Officer to be deployed to the operation at the same time.
    - Neither can deploy (when alone) unless they are confident CIC can be managed in their absence.
-    If there is a [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] the Executive Officer requires permission to deploy, whereas the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] only needs to notify the command team, if there isn't then the Executive Officer must also notify their command team.
        - [color=#cb0000]Abuse of this by either role may result in OOC consequences[/color].
- Only the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] can directly appoint Honor Guards for their own protection -- Executive Officers must ask for permission from the CO to do so.
- The provisions for either of the Commanders are non-transferable; a third person, be it officer or enlisted, cannot be appointed the role of acting CO/XO as a substitute for the above deployment regulations.

[head=3]Conditions[/head]

[color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officers[/color] who deploy must be aware of the following conditions:

You may only deploy if you absolutely trust your CIC staff to run the operation in your absence. Do not deploy if you feel your CIC staff would be incapable of running the operation without your personal guidance.
All actions taken by the CIC in your absence are your responsibility. Do not deploy if you do not believe the CIC is capable of handling itself without your direction.
A [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] who dies or is captured at the frontline will not be subject to reprimands unless it is discovered they have done so recklessly and with disregard to the above conditions and rules.


[head=3]Frontline Command[/head]

While deployed, the CO’s job is still to command and communicate frequently with both the CIC and marine crews groundside, not do combat. They are a leader, not a fighter.

Direct engagements should be reserved to when you are assisting the Marines in a support capacity, spearheading an offensive maneuver, or in defense of others or of self. COs should avoid taking point unnecessarily or otherwise opening themselves up to being killed or captured very easily. They should remain close to Marines and prioritize facilitating clear orders and command above engaging in combat.
