[head=2]ARES AI Core ([color=#cb0000]Non-Modifiable[/color])[/head]

Access to the direct AI core is strictly by appointment only. Only Working Joes, AI Service Technicians (USCM or Weyland-Yutani), the ship's [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], the ship's Synthetic(s) and the ship's Chief Engineer have free access (no ticket required).

The AI Core is the direct responsibility of any active AI Service Technician assigned to the ship. The assigned AIST is authorized to remove any personnel present in the core, with the exception of pre-authorized personnel listed above, should they deem it necessary. In the absence of an assigned AIST, though not in the case of their death, the responsibility falls to the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], and then to the Chief Engineer.

- Prior to any authorized appointments, identifiable weapons should be deposited into the repository by the reception desk, to be retrieved after an appointment has concluded.

    - With the exception of the pre-authenticated personnel listed above, or Military Police responding to a legitimate security threat, anyone bringing weapons into the AI Core lose their right to access and may result in Core Security Protocols being engaged.

- Access rights are non-transferable and, with the exception of Working Joes and AISTs, only ARES may grant other personnel lawful access to the AI Core, through Access Ticket requests.

[head=3]Core Security Protocols[/head]

ARES is equipped with various capabilities to ensure the AI Core remains safe during times of emergency. These capabilities are outlined below.

- ARES, via the use of Working Joes, is authorized to remove trespassers by physical force.

- Where circumstances pose a serious threat to the continued function of the AI Core ARES, or Working Joes, may initiate a Core Lockdown resulting in security doors sealing all access routes and arming the automated sentry guns located in the Core Chamber.

    - Should lockdown procedures be ineffective or compromised CN-20 Nerve Gas may be deployed from security vents with the intent to incapacitate intruders to the core.
