[head=2]Department SOP and Heads of Staff[/head]

Specific Department orders and their standard procedures are listed here. These should always be followed and carried out by the department personnel. The head of the department holds responsibility for their department and answers directly to the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] of the ship. Department heads are not allowed to deploy to the AO, with the exception of the Chief Engineer. Following this, anyone that intends to deploy, including Staff Officers, requires permission from either the head of their department or the [color=#007f00]Commander[/head], where the [color=#007f00]Commander[/head] can overrule the department head.


[head=3]Medical[/head]

The Chief Medical Officer has final say over the medbay and medical procedures onboard the Almayer, except when overridden by the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color]. They may authorize or prohibit experiments at their discretion, set medbay procedures, and fire or hire civilians working in their department. They may only fire medbay staff in the case they have performed a Marine Law violation. When in medbay all personnel, excluding the Commander, are required to listen to and obey the orders of the CMO. During Delta Emergency Alerts, any medical personnel is to either get to the escape pods and evacuate the ship, or hold in safe locations with marines, to provide medical support for the wounded troops.

- It is a crime to smoke within the medical bay or sugical theatres.


[head=3]Requisitions[/head]

The Quartermaster has control over the requisitions bay and the right to decline service to any member of the crew, including officers. No equipment may be taken from the Requisitions Bay by non-requisitions personnel without the QM or ASO’s approval. Their decisions on such matters may only be overridden by the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color]. During Delta Emergency Alerts, the Requisitions Department is to follow orders from Command. All Requisitions personnel are to join standard marines in either holding the Almayer or Evacuate the ship as well as getting Civilian personnel to safety, depending on the orders given by the Command Staff.


[head=3]Engineering[/head]

The Chief Engineer is in charge of modifications made to the ship as well as performing repairs, maintenance, and overall structure changes, they are also ultimately responsible for the construction of the Forward Operating Base. The CE is still required to follow the Ship modifications SOP and is subservient to the Auxilliary Support Officer. During Delta Emergency Alerts, the Engineering Department is to follow orders from Command. All Engineering personnel are to join standard marines in either holding the Almayer or Evacuating the ship, as well as getting Civilian personnel into safety, depending on the orders given by the Command Staff.

The Ordnance Technicians are a part of the Engineering department.
The CE is allowed to deploy to the FOB if there’s an XO on board, and they require permission from the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] or Auxilliary Support Officer. They may deploy with the purpose of building the FOB, securing Tcomms, etc. and must leave should it fall under siege.
In the absence of an ASO, the Chief Engineer must remain aboard the ship.
