[head=2]Employment Regulations[/head]

[head=3]Demotion and Termination Procedure[/head]

For crimes with the punishment of demotion or termination USCM affiliated personnel may be demoted to a more junior position within their department (or into the Operations department in the XO’s case) If that position does not exist, they can be terminated. Should the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] wish, they may turn any demotion to a termination instead allowing them access only to the common areas of the ship. A Duty Officer is unable to do this.


[head=3]Employment Procedure[/head]

Personnel recovered from the Area of Operations may be temporarily employed in the Requisitions, Engineering or Medical department according to their skills or join the forces of USCM if the current [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] allows it under the rank of PVT. Employed personnel must be given an ID identifying them in their new position and given access to their work area. Employed personnel are given a junior position and must obey the orders of all Almayer personnel assigned to that department. A Duty Officer is unable to do this.


[head=3]Restricted Areas and Access Modification[/head]

Personnel may only legally access areas their ID grants them passage to unless someone responsible for the area allows them entry. The [color=#007f00]Commander[/head] may restrict anyone from accessing any area of the ship. Heads of Staff may evict anyone from their departments except the [color=#007f00]Commander[/head] or the Duty Officer.

The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/head] may modify the access afforded to any person’s ID card at will. (No all-access| Server Rules). The [color=#007f00]Commander[/head] may modify access to all departments and grant access to all departments with the Head of Department's approval. During emergencies, such as missing Command Staff, officers may modify their own access if required.

Anyone with access to a department may grant others temporary physical (non-ID) access to that area but may be overruled by the head of the department. The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/head] can overrule the department head, but a regular [color=#007f00]Commander[/head] may not.