[head=1]Standard Operating Procedure[/head]

Verbiage:
To ensure clarity within this document certain terms are used for certain things. Here is a small list to help promote clarity.

- [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color]: A whitelisted USCM Commanding Officer. Anything with the words Commanding Officer only applies to Whitelisted USCM Commanding Officers. These rights cannot be transferred.

- [color=#027602]Commander[/color]: The current Commander of this ship. Anything that mentions the Commander also applies to acting Commanders. These rights are transferable to any new Commander, proceeding down the Chain of Command.

- In the event of the current [color=#0027602]Commander[/color] deploying, or being rendered temporarily incapable of command; [color=#0027602]Commander[/color] rights (with some exceptions) are also applied to the next in command (so long as they're still aboard the ship) as Duty Officer alongside the Commander.

- Examples of the [color=#0027602]Commander[/color] being temporarily incapable of command of the ship:
    Communications are offline for an extended period, or unable to be restored due to extreme danger and Commander is missing & unreachable by telephone.
    Commander deploys into the field.
- Examples of the [color=#0027602]Commander[/color] being permanently incapable, wherein next in command becomes the new Commander.
    Commander is dead and beyond rescue.
    Commander is relieved of duty due to arrest or mutiny.
    Communications are lost with the field while Commander is deployed, and are unlikely to be restored.
- Duty Officer: The ranking person according to the Chain of Command who, in the absence of the Commander is nominally in command of the ship. Except where explicitly stated otherwise Duty Officer is interchangable with, and inherits the rights of, Commander.

- [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color]: [color=#cb0000]Chief of Military Police[/color]. The Chief MP is usually the second highest authority of marine law in the AO. The rights of the Chief MP are not transferrable excepting where specifically also given to the Military Warden as another MP may be appointed to acting Warden by the Commander.

- [color=#cb0000]MP[/color]: [color=#cb0000]Military police[/color]. These rights also include deputized XO’s, SO’s, or Synthetics who are dealing with Marine Law. These rights cannot be transferred.

- Officer: A person who is commissioned into the USCM and thus Commissioned Officers. These rights cannot be transferred.

For all other roles and mentions, a specific person can be appointed if the specific role is not available, but the chain of command should be followed if possible. This also means these rights are transferable. Only the current Commander may appoint people to a new position.



[head=2]Foreword: The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color][/head]
The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] of a vessel holds certain privileges as outlined in Marine Law. Additionally, they may alter any aspect of Standard Operating Procedure (unless otherwise noted) so long as these alterations do not contradict Marine Law. Should there be concerns about the exercise of this privilege, any personnel may contact High Command to inquire about the legitimacy of such changes and request they be overturned, The Commanding Officer may also face punishment. This privilege is not extended to anyone taking up command in the Commanding Officer’s absence.

- Military Police must be informed of any changes made to the SOP before its implemented.

- The SOP may not be modified to the extent of griefing or physically burdening marines. Modifications such as “marines must walk only” are prohibited, as is modifying SOP to imprison a marine for a custom offense with malicious intent.

- Standard-issued equipment to Marines that can be found in their squad preparations and requisitions can not be restricted or prohibited in any way. Marines reserve the right to freely carry and use the equipment they are provided with.

- SOP modifications are changes to SOP. They are not exceptions for specific people or groups, and apply universally to the whole AO.


[head=2]General Regulations[/head]

[head=1]Rules of Engagement[/head]

The following are the standard rules of engagement. They may be modified by the Commander as necessary in accordance with AO developments.

- Any potentially useful equipment found in the AO such as weapons or tools may be requisitioned for military use by any USCM personnel with the rank of SGT and above.

- Buildings and obstacles within the AO may be constructed or deconstructed in accordance with strategic or tactical directives. The use of plastic explosives is authorized for demolitions.

- Wildlife is not to be needlessly hunted if passive. Any hostile wildlife or wildlife that approaches the perimeter of FOBs, supply lines or compromises the personal space of marines or their formation may be shot on sight.

- Humans that are not overtly hostiles are to be halted and their intentions uncovered. Survivors are to be debriefed and be given the option to board the Almayer as a passenger, they may be offered this freely.

- Other military or paramilitary entities may be allowed to continue their operations if they prove beneficial or indifferent to USCM interests.

- The use of force is authorized to disable non-compliant personnel. Hostile personnel may be killed on sight.


[head=2]Equipment[/head]

[head=1]Standard issue equipment[/head]

Standard issue equipment is defined as any military uniform, armor, weapon or accessory personnel may find in their crew locker, as well as those they emerge from cryosleep with and any equipment normally available for issue by the Requisitions Department.

Additionally, the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] may issue special equipment on a case by case basis, such as special headsets for ease of communications or special weaponry for certain marines or squads so long as it does not contradict Marine Law. Heads of Staff may also assign their spare headsets to members of their department. Alcohol may be stored in the Officer’s Mess, Commanding Officer’s Mess, Commanding Officer’s Quarters and CL’s Private Quarters.


[head=1]Uniform Regulations[/head]

USCM and USCM-affiliated personnel are required to be wearing appropriate clothing during operations. Marines and MPs should be wearing their uniform, boots, and armor at a minimum. Other crew must wear their uniform and assigned footwear, or a standard issue replacement. Headwear, if any is worn, must be your properly assigned headgear, or an acceptable replacement.

- The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] may not authorize an SOP change for uniform regulations to allow personnel to deploy without clothes or a lack of uniform.

- Department specific uniforms and headgear are limited to the persons within that department unless given out by the head of the department or [color=#027602]Commander[/color].

    - MP's must always use their department-specific headgear.

    - One should not use other head of department's uniforms or headgear unless approved by ones own head of department.

    - One is free to fold or otherwise shorten their uniform at their discretion.

    - The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] retains the right to enforce the wearing of helmets by key personnel, namely Squad Leaders, Fireteam Leaders, Specialists and/or Smartgunners.

- Shipside crew should not be in combat armor unless the ship is on a security alert, or they are deploying to a combat zone.

    - The exceptions to this are Military Police, Intelligence Officers and flight crew as some form of combat armor is typically necessary for their jobs.


[head=1]Equipment Handling Procedure[/head]

Aboard the ship, weapons must have their safety on or be holstered when not in use. Marines must be allowed to enable safety on the first offence. If the same marine violates Equipment Handling Procedure again, disciplinary measures may be taken. Under normal circumstances, weapons may only be fired in the firing range. Weaponry may not be left unattended unless it is properly secured in spaces intended for it (weapon racks, gun cabinets, etc.).

Pills must be within a pill bottle. All reagent-containing medical equipment (syringes, pill bottles, autoinjectors) must be labelled with accurate content and dosing information. Surgical tools, and other medical devices must be placed within their designated containers (surgery trays, medical bags, etc.)


[head=1]Authorized Weapons - Code Restrictions[/head]
- Code Green - Authorized Weapons may be carried by deploying marines (any standard issue weapon or weapon ordered from requisitions) and security (non-lethals and sidearms only, not riot gear such as beanbags). Any personnel issued with a weapon upon the start of an operation may retain it, and Commissioned officers may carry sidearms so long as this does not inhibit their standard duties.
Long/Large bladed weapons (Machetes, Axes, Katanas etc.) are treated in the same respect as firearms in terms of carry restrictions.
Civilians are excluded from the right to retain issued weapons, unless they are deploying to a combat zone. Otherwise these weapons must be kept secure in personal quarters or armories.
Personnel who abuse their right to a sidearm can have this revoked by the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] or, excluding equal or higher ranks, the Chief MP.
The Chief MP or Military Warden may authorise or use Riot Equipment on Code Green so long as this use remains exclusively inside the Brig, for training or defensive purposes.

- Code Blue - All crew are authorized pistols. [color=#cb0000]Military Police[/color] may carry lethal weapons to subdue external threats. [color=#cb0000]Military Police[/head] may use non-lethal riot gear to subdue Marines during a Mutiny or large gatherings of insubordinate personnel. Flashbangs are considered a Riot tool.

- Code Red - No Weapon Restrictions.

- Code Delta - Normally happens when one of the Dropships crashes on the Almayer. You are authorized to use ANY kind of weaponry. The acting [color=#027602]Commander[/color] may order a general Evacuation, Self Destruction of the ship, or hold the Almayer.

Exception: Firearm use and possession are allowed if you or someone you are responsible for are in immediate, life-threatening danger and the appropriate code-level has not been set.


[head=2]Department SOP and Heads of Staff[/head]

Specific Department orders and their standard procedures are listed here. These should always be followed and carried out by the department personnel. The head of the department holds responsibility for their department and answers directly to the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] of the ship. Department heads are not allowed to deploy to the AO, with the exception of the Chief Engineer. Following this, anyone that intends to deploy, including Staff Officers, requires permission from either the head of their department or the [color=#027602]Commander[/head], where the [color=#027602]Commander[/head] can overrule the department head.


[head=3]Medical[/head]

The Chief Medical Officer has final say over the medbay and medical procedures onboard the Almayer, except when overridden by the [color=#027602]Commander[/color]. They may authorize or prohibit experiments at their discretion, set medbay procedures, and fire or hire civilians working in their department. They may only fire medbay staff in the case they have performed a Marine Law violation. When in medbay all personnel, excluding the Commander, are required to listen to and obey the orders of the CMO. During Delta Emergency Alerts, any medical personnel is to either get to the escape pods and evacuate the ship, or hold in safe locations with marines, to provide medical support for the wounded troops.

- It is a crime to smoke within the medical bay or sugical theatres.


[head=3]Requisitions[/head]

The Quartermaster has control over the requisitions bay and the right to decline service to any member of the crew, including officers. No equipment may be taken from the Requisitions Bay by non-requisitions personnel without the QM or ASO’s approval. Their decisions on such matters may only be overridden by the [color=#027602]Commander[/color]. During Delta Emergency Alerts, the Requisitions Department is to follow orders from Command. All Requisitions personnel are to join standard marines in either holding the Almayer or Evacuate the ship as well as getting Civilian personnel to safety, depending on the orders given by the Command Staff.


[head=3]Engineering[/head]

The Chief Engineer is in charge of modifications made to the ship as well as performing repairs, maintenance, and overall structure changes, they are also ultimately responsible for the construction of the Forward Operating Base. The CE is still required to follow the Ship modifications SOP and is subservient to the Auxilliary Support Officer. During Delta Emergency Alerts, the Engineering Department is to follow orders from Command. All Engineering personnel are to join standard marines in either holding the Almayer or Evacuating the ship, as well as getting Civilian personnel into safety, depending on the orders given by the Command Staff.

The Ordnance Technicians are a part of the Engineering department.
The CE is allowed to deploy to the FOB if there’s an XO on board, and they require permission from the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] or Auxilliary Support Officer. They may deploy with the purpose of building the FOB, securing Tcomms, etc. and must leave should it fall under siege.
In the absence of an ASO, the Chief Engineer must remain aboard the ship.


[head=2]ARES AI Core ([color=#cb0000]Non-Modifiable[/color])[/head]

Access to the direct AI core is strictly by appointment only. Only Working Joes, AI Service Technicians (USCM or Weyland-Yutani), the ship's [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], the ship's Synthetic(s) and the ship's Chief Engineer have free access (no ticket required).

The AI Core is the direct responsibility of any active AI Service Technician assigned to the ship. The assigned AIST is authorized to remove any personnel present in the core, with the exception of pre-authorized personnel listed above, should they deem it necessary. In the absence of an assigned AIST, though not in the case of their death, the responsibility falls to the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], and then to the Chief Engineer.

- Prior to any authorized appointments, identifiable weapons should be deposited into the repository by the reception desk, to be retrieved after an appointment has concluded.

    - With the exception of the pre-authenticated personnel listed above, or Military Police responding to a legitimate security threat, anyone bringing weapons into the AI Core lose their right to access and may result in Core Security Protocols being engaged.

- Access rights are non-transferable and, with the exception of Working Joes and AISTs, only ARES may grant other personnel lawful access to the AI Core, through Access Ticket requests.

[head=3]Core Security Protocols[/head]

ARES is equipped with various capabilities to ensure the AI Core remains safe during times of emergency. These capabilities are outlined below.

- ARES, via the use of Working Joes, is authorized to remove trespassers by physical force.

- Where circumstances pose a serious threat to the continued function of the AI Core ARES, or Working Joes, may initiate a Core Lockdown resulting in security doors sealing all access routes and arming the automated sentry guns located in the Core Chamber.

    - Should lockdown procedures be ineffective or compromised CN-20 Nerve Gas may be deployed from security vents with the intent to incapacitate intruders to the core.


[head=2]Security ([color=#cb0000]Non-Modifiable[/color])[/head]

The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] has the final say on law enforcement in their operational area as outlined in Marine Law. It is the duty of the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] to ensure the procedure is observed and the law is carried out in a just manner. Should the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] believe the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] is abusing their position, they must contact High Command for permission to relieve him.

MPs have a duty to enforce Marine Law and ensure order is maintained, and breaking Marine Law would incur in neglect of duty charges. To this end, other members of the crew may not interfere with their actions when enforcing the law, such as barring them from entering an area if they have reason to be there. However, when ordered to, MPs must leave sensitive areas such as Operation Theatres unless performing an arrest. Additionally, MPs have a duty to keep the ship and shipside crew safe. In such matters, they must obey the orders of officers in accordance with their position within the ship.

Upon request by CIC personnel (Acting [color=#027602]Commander[/color], [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], Executive Officer, Staff Officers), up to two volunteers from the Military Police may be deployed to the FOB to protect deployed shipside crew stationed within the safe zone (not to be confused with CO Escort Missions). This can be overridden by higher-ranking personnel, with the Acting [color=#027602]Commander[/color] having the final say.

- At least one MP must remain on the ship at all times. Should there be a [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] they must be the one to remain, or in their absence the Warden.


[head=3]Use of Listening Devices[/head]

The use of radio transmissive listening devices is highly restrictive aboard USCM ships and in operation zones.

Military Police are authorized to use listening devices within the Brig at their discretion, and do not need to request permission to use them there. Any use of listening devices by Military Police outside of the Brig however must adhere to the requirements detailed below.

1. Military Police must receive permission from the [color=#027602]Commander[/color], or in their absence the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color], to deploy a listening device in any area outside of the Brig

2. The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] may only authorize deployment of a listening device if there is reasonable suspicion of intent to commit or conspire to commit crimes in that area.

3. Military Police cannot break or enter, nor have someone else do so, into an area they do not have access to in order to place listening devices.

The use of 3rd party listening devices aboard USCM ships is strictly forbidden and will be prosecuted.


[head=2]Ship modifications[/head]
The ship may only be modified with approval from the [color=#027602]Commander[/color]. The Chief Engineer can also approve changes to the ship, but should it affect a department it requires the Head of Department to approve of it as well. The Military Police must be notified of changes being made prior to them taking effect.

- The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] has final authority over changes on board the ship.
    
    - Changes to the Brig and CIC are forbidden should those changes compromise security or capability to detain personnel.

- Dismantling elements of the ship to utilise materials for operations is forbidden unless severe enemy contact is confirmed.
    
    - This is defined by enemy contact wherein containment and operational security requires significantly more resources than are immediately to hand. Military Police or other personnel may fax High Command or Provost to contest a decision made by the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] as to whether the situation requires dismantling parts of the ship.
       
        - A fax is not required should these changes be conducted prior to hostile contact being established.
   
    - Removal of vendors or machines does not constitute illegal modification of the ship unless the act of doing so alters the functionalty or purpose of a specific area.
     
        - Moving medical vendors aboard a dropship does not constitute altering functionality unless it impacts the use of medbay itself.

- A Duty Officer is unable to authorise shipside modifications.


[head=1][color=#cb0000]Non-Modifiable[/color] Standard Operating Procedure[/head]

The SOP written below may only be modified with High Command's permission and not solely by the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color].


[head=2]Nuclear Protocol[/head]

In the event of nuclear ordnance being deployed in the AO all personnel are authorized to deploy to the FOB to protect it during countdown, overriding departmental SOPs preventing deployments.

- The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] may order personnel to remain aboard the ship at their discretion during Nuclear Protocols.

- This does not allow prisoners to be deployed.


[head=2]Command and Control[/head]

[head=3]Forward Operating Bases[/head]

When establishing a Forward Operating Base (FOB), the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] in charge of an operation should take the minimum precautions to ensure security and defense for stationed Marines and incoming land, air, or sea transports.

- The primary extraction point, such as aircraft landing zones (LZs), are to be reinforced with a minimum line of non-makeshift defenses to prevent immediate enemy breaching.

- FOBs do not have to be placed adjacent to an extraction point, nor does one have to exist at all. However, the extraction point itself must at least be properly defended and guarded.

- Additional combat outposts (COPs) may be established far away from the primary FOB for forward deployment and staging.

- Personnel normally restricted to shipside duties such as doctors and Military Police may be deployed to a FOB freely; however special circumstances or clearances are needed, either via the CO or via the relevant department head, if not conflicting with Marine Law or SOP, to proceed outside the FOB.


[head=3]Field Deployment[/head]

The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] and The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] have the right to deploy themselves to the frontline for the sake of commanding their troops from a more direct point of view than a ship’s Combat Information Centre. Deployments must be made for the sake of the troops, not for the personal glory or agenda of the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] themselves. This right does not extend to the Duty Officer.


[head=3]Deployment Prerequisites[/head]

Executive Officers are allowed to deploy in a Commanding Officer’s stead for leadership and are subject to the same regulations and standards as a CO.

For this passage, both the CO and XO together are referred to as the “Commanders”.

Should either the Commanding Officer or Executive Officer deploy, several rules must be followed:

- It is inadvised for the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] and Executive Officer to be deployed to the operation at the same time.
    - Neither can deploy (when alone) unless they are confident CIC can be managed in their absence.
-    If there is a [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] the Executive Officer requires permission to deploy, whereas the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] only needs to notify the command team, if there isn't then the Executive Officer must also notify their command team.
        - Abuse of this by either role may result in OOC consequences.
- Only the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] can directly appoint Honor Guards for their own protection -- Executive Officers must ask for permission from the CO to do so.
- The provisions for either of the Commanders are non-transferable; a third person, be it officer or enlisted, cannot be appointed the role of acting CO/XO as a substitute for the above deployment regulations.


[head=3]Conditions[/head]

[color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officers[/color] who deploy must be aware of the following conditions:

You may only deploy if you absolutely trust your CIC staff to run the operation in your absence. Do not deploy if you feel your CIC staff would be incapable of running the operation without your personal guidance.
All actions taken by the CIC in your absence are your responsibility. Do not deploy if you do not believe the CIC is capable of handling itself without your direction.
A [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] who dies or is captured at the frontline will not be subject to reprimands unless it is discovered they have done so recklessly and with disregard to the above conditions and rules.


[head=3]Frontline Command[/head]

While deployed, the CO’s job is still to command and communicate frequently with both the CIC and marine crews groundside, not do combat. They are a leader, not a fighter.

Direct engagements should be reserved to when you are assisting the Marines in a support capacity, spearheading an offensive maneuver, or in defense of others or of self. COs should avoid taking point unnecessarily or otherwise opening themselves up to being killed or captured very easily. They should remain close to Marines and prioritize facilitating clear orders and command above engaging in combat.


[head=3]Conduct of Briefing[/head]

The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] or [color=#027602]Commander[/color] is to ensure a proper briefing before any operation is being held. The briefing should be performed in an area where a proper inspection of ready personnel and personnel can hear any orders. Areas that interfere with non-combat personnel or support personnel shall be avoided (Medbay, Research, Dropship) It is recommended to use the briefing room, conference room, or an open area such as the Hanger.

The briefing performed must at least involve the Squad Leaders as well as CiC personnel, which includes the on-duty Staff Officers, unless they are performing other essential roles. Failure to adhere to this will incur Neglect of Duty Charges.

- The commander may excuse Staff Officers from Briefing at their discretion, provided they inform the Military Police beforehand.
- This procedure may be skipped in the event of Delta alert or another Emergency situation.


[head=3]Armories[/head]

Special equipment found in armories such as Mk221s is not allowed to be handed out to non-officers without a clear, understandable, and urgent reason behind doing so. The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer's[/color] M46C is not to be handed out.

One may not send items stored in the Armory as part of a supply drop, give them away as rewards/prizes, or form a squad that uses such equipment as standard.

- The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] may hand them out to deploying CIC staff as part of their standard equipment.
- Armory equipment may be handed out to all personnel during boarding or a Code Red or Delta scenario. Officers should be prioritized before enlisted.


[head=3]Third-Party Personnel[/head]

Marines are encouraged to peacefully recover any third-party personnel found in an area of operations and offer them refuge within their ship. All personnel recovered from a combat zone must be searched on arrival and their weapons and unauthorized items secured within the Brig performed by the MP's. They may keep their clothes and tools, provided they are not used for criminal purposes.

Survivors may refuse to answer questions and use their right to remain silent. They may not be punished for this.
Should the civilians deploy to the area of operations again they may request to be given back their gear and an MP must escort them to the dropship to make sure they deploy. Returning Civilians will have to be searched again but may skip the medical check.
They must also be provided with adequate medical care and sustenance. Civilian personnel recovered may be given a temporary junior position in a department or join the USCM should their qualifications allow for it as outlined in the Employment procedure by the [color=#027602]Commander[/color]. Survivors employed by the USCM may keep their weapons if their position permits them to be armed.

Third-Party Military or Paramilitary forces may be allowed to keep their weaponry, provided their presence is beneficial to the operation.


[head=3]Eviction of Survivors[/head]

Survivors can only be evicted or denied access to the ship in these cases: The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] can overrule either decision and the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] may overrule the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color].

Should a survivor commit a Major crime the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] or [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] may choose to evict them or refuse entrance to the Ship after their sentence has been completed. Once the survivor is evicted, they are barred from boarding the Ship again.
Should the survivor be confirmed to have any confirmed ties to a military or paramilitary organization. The [color=#027602]Commander[/color] or [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] may bar the person from boarding.
The Duty Officer, if there is one, is unable to evict survivors with the exception of where their crimes are of a violent nature.


[head=2]Employment Regulations[/head]

[head=2]Demotion and Termination Procedure[/head]

For crimes with the punishment of demotion or termination USCM affiliated personnel may be demoted to a more junior position within their department (or into the Operations department in the XO’s case) If that position does not exist, they can be terminated. Should the [color=#027602]Commander[/color] wish, they may turn any demotion to a termination instead allowing them access only to the common areas of the ship. A Duty Officer is unable to do this.


[head=2]Employment Procedure[/head]

Personnel recovered from the Area of Operations may be temporarily employed in the Requisitions, Engineering or Medical department according to their skills or join the forces of USCM if the current [color=#027602]Commander[/color] allows it under the rank of PVT. Employed personnel must be given an ID identifying them in their new position and given access to their work area. Employed personnel are given a junior position and must obey the orders of all Almayer personnel assigned to that department. A Duty Officer is unable to do this.


[head=2]Restricted Areas and Access Modification[/head]

Personnel may only legally access areas their ID grants them passage to unless someone responsible for the area allows them entry. The [color=#027602]Commander[/head] may restrict anyone from accessing any area of the ship. Heads of Staff may evict anyone from their departments except the [color=#027602]Commander[/head] or the Duty Officer.

The [color=#027602]Commanding Officer[/head] may modify the access afforded to any person’s ID card at will. (No all-access| Server Rules). The [color=#027602]Commander[/head] may modify access to all departments and grant access to all departments with the Head of Department's approval. During emergencies, such as missing Command Staff, officers may modify their own access if required.

Anyone with access to a department may grant others temporary physical (non-ID) access to that area but may be overruled by the head of the department. The [color=#027602]Commanding Officer[/head] can overrule the department head, but a regular [color=#027602]Commander[/head] may not.