[head=2]Equipment[/head]

[head=1]Standard issue equipment[/head]

Standard issue equipment is defined as any military uniform, armor, weapon or accessory personnel may find in their crew locker, as well as those they emerge from cryosleep with and any equipment normally available for issue by the Requisitions Department.

Additionally, the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] may issue special equipment on a case by case basis, such as special headsets for ease of communications or special weaponry for certain marines or squads so long as it does not contradict Marine Law. Heads of Staff may also assign their spare headsets to members of their department. Alcohol may be stored in the Officer’s Mess, Commanding Officer’s Mess, Commanding Officer’s Quarters and CL’s Private Quarters.


[head=3]Uniform Regulations[/head]

USCM and USCM-affiliated personnel are required to be wearing appropriate clothing during operations. Marines and MPs should be wearing their uniform, boots, and armor at a minimum. Other crew must wear their uniform and assigned footwear, or a standard issue replacement. Headwear, if any is worn, must be your properly assigned headgear, or an acceptable replacement.

- The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] may not authorize an SOP change for uniform regulations to allow personnel to deploy without clothes or a lack of uniform.

- Department specific uniforms and headgear are limited to the persons within that department unless given out by the head of the department or [color=#007f00]Commander[/color].

    - MP's must always use their department-specific headgear.

    - One should not use other head of department's uniforms or headgear unless approved by ones own head of department.

    - One is free to fold or otherwise shorten their uniform at their discretion.

    - The [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] retains the right to enforce the wearing of helmets by key personnel, namely Squad Leaders, Fireteam Leaders, Specialists and/or Smartgunners.

- Shipside crew should not be in combat armor unless the ship is on a security alert, or they are deploying to a combat zone.

    - The exceptions to this are Military Police, Intelligence Officers and flight crew as some form of combat armor is typically necessary for their jobs.


[head=3]Equipment Handling Procedure[/head]

Aboard the ship, weapons must have their safety on or be holstered when not in use. Marines must be allowed to enable safety on the first offence. If the same marine violates Equipment Handling Procedure again, disciplinary measures may be taken. Under normal circumstances, weapons may only be fired in the firing range. Weaponry may not be left unattended unless it is properly secured in spaces intended for it (weapon racks, gun cabinets, etc.).

Pills must be within a pill bottle. All reagent-containing medical equipment (syringes, pill bottles, autoinjectors) must be labelled with accurate content and dosing information. Surgical tools, and other medical devices must be placed within their designated containers (surgery trays, medical bags, etc.)