[head=2]Security ([color=#cb0000]Non-Modifiable[/color])[/head]

The [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] has the final say on law enforcement in their operational area as outlined in Marine Law. It is the duty of the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] to ensure the procedure is observed and the law is carried out in a just manner. Should the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] believe the [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color] is abusing their position, they must contact High Command for permission to relieve him.

MPs have a duty to enforce Marine Law and ensure order is maintained, and breaking Marine Law would incur in neglect of duty charges. To this end, other members of the crew may not interfere with their actions when enforcing the law, such as barring them from entering an area if they have reason to be there. However, when ordered to, MPs must leave sensitive areas such as Operation Theatres unless performing an arrest. Additionally, MPs have a duty to keep the ship and shipside crew safe. In such matters, they must obey the orders of officers in accordance with their position within the ship.

Upon request by CIC personnel (Acting [color=#007f00]Commander[/color], [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color], Executive Officer, Staff Officers), up to two volunteers from the Military Police may be deployed to the FOB to protect deployed shipside crew stationed within the safe zone (not to be confused with CO Escort Missions). This can be overridden by higher-ranking personnel, with the Acting [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] having the final say.

- At least one MP must remain on the ship at all times. Should there be a [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color] they must be the one to remain, or in their absence the Warden.


[head=3]Use of Listening Devices[/head]

The use of radio transmissive listening devices is highly restrictive aboard USCM ships and in operation zones.

Military Police are authorized to use listening devices within the Brig at their discretion, and do not need to request permission to use them there. Any use of listening devices by Military Police outside of the Brig however must adhere to the requirements detailed below.

1. Military Police must receive permission from the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color], or in their absence the [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color], to deploy a listening device in any area outside of the Brig

2. The [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] may only authorize deployment of a listening device if there is reasonable suspicion of intent to commit or conspire to commit crimes in that area.

3. Military Police cannot break or enter, nor have someone else do so, into an area they do not have access to in order to place listening devices.

The use of 3rd party listening devices aboard USCM ships is strictly forbidden and will be prosecuted.

