[head=1]Standard Operating Procedure[/head]

Verbiage:
To ensure clarity within this document certain terms are used for certain things. Here is a small list to help promote clarity.

- [color=#01c4f6]Commanding Officer[/color]: A whitelisted USCM Commanding Officer. Anything with the words Commanding Officer only applies to Whitelisted USCM Commanding Officers. These rights cannot be transferred.

- [color=#007f00]Commander[/color]: The current Commander of this ship. Anything that mentions the Commander also applies to acting Commanders. These rights are transferable to any new Commander, proceeding down the Chain of Command.

- In the event of the current [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] deploying, or being rendered temporarily incapable of command; [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] rights (with some exceptions) are also applied to the next in command (so long as they're still aboard the ship) as Duty Officer alongside the Commander.

- Examples of the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] being temporarily incapable of command of the ship:
    Communications are offline for an extended period, or unable to be restored due to extreme danger and Commander is missing & unreachable by telephone.
    Commander deploys into the field.
- Examples of the [color=#007f00]Commander[/color] being permanently incapable, wherein next in command becomes the new Commander.
    Commander is dead and beyond rescue.
    Commander is relieved of duty due to arrest or mutiny.
    Communications are lost with the field while Commander is deployed, and are unlikely to be restored.
- Duty Officer: The ranking person according to the Chain of Command who, in the absence of the Commander is nominally in command of the ship. Except where explicitly stated otherwise Duty Officer is interchangable with, and inherits the rights of, Commander.

- [color=#cb0000]Chief MP[/color]: [color=#cb0000]Chief of Military Police[/color]. The Chief MP is usually the second highest authority of marine law in the AO. The rights of the Chief MP are not transferrable excepting where specifically also given to the Military Warden as another MP may be appointed to acting Warden by the Commander.

- [color=#cb0000]MP[/color]: [color=#cb0000]Military police[/color]. These rights also include deputized XO’s, SO’s, or Synthetics who are dealing with Marine Law. These rights cannot be transferred.

- Officer: A person who is commissioned into the USCM and thus Commissioned Officers. These rights cannot be transferred.

For all other roles and mentions, a specific person can be appointed if the specific role is not available, but the chain of command should be followed if possible. This also means these rights are transferable. Only the current Commander may appoint people to a new position.
